{
    "id": "3a0221d8009b4b19b1227ea82582d26e",
    "title": "Inversion",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "e27d4a6d18fe453397e67f92651f660e",
            "title": "Inversion",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I wondered what time …………………… starting.",
                    "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was the show",
                        "the show was"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She asked me what ……………………….. thinking about.",
                    "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was I",
                        "I was"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I wondered who ………………………",
                    "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "had left the door open",
                        "the door had left open"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "What a lovely place ………………………….!",
                    "description": "The auxiliary verb usually goes after the subject in exclamations with how and what.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is Shimla",
                        "Shimla is"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "How beautiful ………………………..!",
                    "description": "The auxiliary verb usually goes after the subject in exclamations with how and what.",
                    "answers": [
                        "are the flowers",
                        "the flowers are"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "At no time ………………………….. aware of what was happening.",
                    "description": "If a negative expression comes at the beginning of a clause, it is usually followed by auxiliary verb + subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "he was",
                        "was he"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Hardly ……………………… arrived when trouble started.",
                    "description": "Inversion is common after words like hardly, seldom, rarely, little or never.",
                    "answers": [
                        "had he",
                        "he had"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Never ……………………….. seen such a mess.",
                    "description": "Inversion is common after words like hardly, seldom, rarely, little or never.",
                    "answers": [
                        "I have",
                        "have I"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Little ……………………….. what she was doing",
                    "description": "Inversion is common after words like hardly, seldom, rarely, little or never.",
                    "answers": [
                        "did she realize",
                        "she realized"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Only then ………………………… what I had done.",
                    "description": "When only comes at the beginning of the sentence, it is followed by an inverted word order. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "did I understand",
                        "I understood"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Not only ………………………. our money, but we were nearly kidnapped.",
                    "description": "When not only comes at the beginning of the sentence, it is followed by an inverted word order. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "we lost",
                        "lost we",
                        "did we lose"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "What a lovely morning ……………………….!",
                    "description": "The auxiliary verb usually goes after the subject in exclamations with how and what.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is it",
                        "it is"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}